freakycreatures.com 2008-12-20

# privacy policy

Privacy Policy

Last updated: March 20, 2008

Abandon Interactive Entertainment, LLC (together with its parent, affiliates, successors and assigns, "Abandon," the "Company" or "we") respects the privacy of its online visitors and recognizes the importance of protecting personally identifiable information when you visit AreYouFreaky.com and MyFreakyCreatures.com (collectively, the "Sites"). This Privacy Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use, and safeguard the personal information you provide to us, and to assist you in making informed decisions when using the Sites, and any of our products and services (collectively, the “Services”). 

Please note that we have special concerns about the privacy of users who are children under the age of 13, as further addressed in the CHILDREN’S PRIVACY section below. 

WHAT INFORMATION IS COLLECTED? 

Abandon collects personal information (sometimes referred to as “personally identifiable information”) from its online visitors on a voluntary basis and only in order to create or enhance our relationship with you. We may collect personal information from you in connection with your participation in activities like priority list or subscription registrations, forums, sweepstakes, contests, games, surveys, and in connection with chats or bulletin boards, or because you want us to furnish you with Services or information. The personal information we ask for is usually your first and last name, e-mail address, phone number, mailing address, and age, subject to special information collection mechanisms regarding children under 18. If you are 18 or older, you are eligible to purchase Services from us, in which event we may require your billing address and credit card information. 

HOW IS THE INFORMATION IS COLLECTED?

Abandon collects personally identifiable information via conventional internet forms. In addition, certain sections of the Sites may use "cookies." Cookies are very small data files left on your computer by the Sites. These files can then be accessed by the Sites in the future. Most browsers are automatically set to accept cookies. Most browsers will allow you to erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block acceptance of cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored; you should refer to your browser instructions or “Help” screen to learn more about how to manage cookies. Please note, however, that if you block cookies, some portions of the Sites and Services may not function properly.

Like most standard websites, we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the Sites and Services, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

INFORMATION USAGE AND DISTRIBUTION: 

Broadly speaking, we use personal information for purposes of administering our business activities and making available other products and services to our visitors and prospective visitors. Occasionally, we may also use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to our Sites and Services and special offers we think you will find valuable. The lists used to send you product and service offers are developed and managed under our standards and those of our service provider, which are designed to safeguard the security and privacy of our visitors' personal information. 

Legal Disclaimer

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on the Sites or its owners.

Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)

We share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personally identifiable information.

Third Party Advertisers

The Sites share usage information about users with reputable third parties for the purpose of targeting our internet banner advertisements on the Sites. The information they collect and share through this technology is not personally identifiable. From time to time you may notice offers from outside companies advertised on the Sites. We take measures to select product or service providers that are reputable. However, we cannot make any representations about the practices and policies of these companies.

Third Party Intermediaries

We share personal information with the credit card processing company and/or internet service providers that we use to bill users for Services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

California Privacy Rights Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of Abandon who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [support@myfreakycreatures.com](mailto:support@myfreakycreatures.com) or write us at: Attn: Abandon CA Privacy Rights, Abandon Interactive Entertainment, LLC, 21355 Pacific Coast Hwy, Suite 101, Malibu, CA 90265.

Business Transactions

In the event that Abandon or the Sites is/are sold or transferred, or in the event that substantially all of Abandon’s assets are sold or transferred to a third party, the Sites and any personally identifiable information collected by us, will be among the transferred assets. By using the Sites, you hereby agree to such transfer or assignment of your personal information collected by Abandon, and you further waive any claims that could be made against us in relation thereto.

DATA SECURITY:

We use reasonable administrative, technical, personnel and physical measures to safeguard your personal information in our possession against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure or modification. In addition, we also use reasonable methods to make sure that your personal information is accurate, up-to-date and appropriately complete.

OPT-OUT / REMOVAL OF PERSONAL INFORMATION:

If you do not want Abandon to send you e-mail or postal mail about our Sites or Services, or if you want to cease use of the Sites and Services and have your personal information removed, you can opt-out at the time of registration or at any time thereafter, or request removal at any time, by contacting Abandon by e-mail at [unsubscribe@myfreakycreatures.com](mailto:unsubscribe@myfreakycreatures.com) or by mailing a request to: Attn: Freaky Creatures Privacy Policy, Abandon Interactive Entertainment, LLC, 21355 Pacific Coast Hwy, Suite 101, Malibu, CA 90265.

IF YOU HAVE QUESTIONS OR COMPLAINTS REGARDING OUR COLLECTION OR USAGE OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION:

If you have any questions, complaints, or comments regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact Abandon by email at [support@myfreakycreatures.com](mailto:support@myfreakycreatures.com) or by writing to: Attn: Freaky Creatures Privacy Policy, Abandon Interactive Entertainment, LLC, 21355 Pacific Coast Hwy, Suite 101, Malibu, CA 90265.

IF YOU REFUSE TO PROVIDE INFORMATION ONLINE:

Abandon does not require registration or submission of personally identifiable information to obtain basic access to the Sites; however, you may not be able to access all areas and functions of the Sites or participate in any Services. 

PUBLIC FORUMS:

Abandon may make chat rooms, message boards, news groups, and other community Services available to you on the Sites. Please understand that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information. Abandon has no control over its use and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personally identifiable information or any other information about yourself. The information presented in these areas reflects the views of the individual users or hosts and does not necessarily reflect the views of Abandon or any of its affiliates.

CHILDREN'S PRIVACY:

The Sites comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). For more information about COPPA and children’s privacy, please visit <http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/privacyinitiatives/childrens.html>. When we use the term “parent” below, we mean to include legal guardians. 

Children under the age of 13

Some areas of the Sites may have special rules for children under the age of 13. When you are in those areas, you must follow those rules.

If a child under 13 wants to use the Sites with Services requiring registration, the only information we would collect from such child during our registration process is the child’s first name, parent's e-mail address, child’s birth date, screen name, and password. We collect birth dates to validate the ages of our guests, including children. We do not collect any other personally identifiable information from children during our registration process. We also will collect a child's e-mail address from a parent for the purpose of sending the child e-mail related to a subscription. For example, we would send a Site newsletter to a child directly at the request of the child's parent. 

We send parents an e-mail requesting affirmative consent to the child’s participation when their child registers on the Sites, registers for Services (including, but not limited to, message boards, instant message or chat features), or enters a sweepstakes or contest. Before allowing a child under 13 to participate in any such activity, we send an e-mail to the child's parent requesting the parent's affirmative consent to the child's participation. If the parent responds by e-mail and gives such consent, we then follow that communication with an e-mail confirmation to the parent and allow the child to participate in the activity. If the parent refuses to allow the child's participation, or if we don’t hear back from the parent within 72 hours, we delete the child's personal information from our database. Once a parent affirmatively permits a child to participate in a Service, sweepstakes or contest, the child will be able to participate in such Service or enter future registration-based sweepstakes or contests without any further notification to the parent. If a child wins a sweepstakes or contest, we notify the parent at the parent's e-mail address provided to us during the registration process, and the parent will have to mail or fax us a signed note at the address or fax number listed in the rules for the specific contest that says it was OK for the child to enter, and tells us they will accept the prize for the child. We may publish a winner's first name, first initial of last name, city, and state of residence on our Web sites. 

Children between the ages of 13 and 18

Do not post your real name on a web site or message board, and never tell anyone online anything private about yourself or your family, including your phone number and address. Use screen names at all times. If you win a sweepstakes that has a prize, your parent will have to mail or fax us a signed note at the address or fax number listed in the rules for the specific contest that says it was OK for you to enter, and tells us they will accept the prize for you. Some areas of the Sites may have special rules for children under the age of 18. When you are in those areas, you must follow those rules.

Information for Parents

Abandon encourages parents to spend time online with their children to become familiar with the types of content available on the internet, including Abandon's online games. Parents should regularly oversee their children's use of e-mail and other online communications and transactional features. Control tools are available from online services and software manufacturers that can help provide a safe online environment for kids.

We do not require a child to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in a contest, game or other activity or Service as a condition of participation. Parents may request a review and/or removal of their child's personal information at any time by sending an e-mail to [remove@myfreakycreatures.com](mailto:remove@myfreakycreatures.com) which must include the same screen name, password, and e-mail address that their child submitted. To protect the child’s privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to verify the parent’s identity before granting him or her access to the child’s personal information. 

LINKS TO THIRD PARTY SITES:

The Sites may from time to time contain links to third-party web sites. Abandon is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. If you are concerned about the privacy policy of a certain third party, you may contact them directly or visit their individual web sites to learn more about their individual privacy policies.

GENERAL TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE / NOTICE OF CHANGES:

The terms of this Privacy Policy are incorporated into our general Terms of Service. Please review our Terms of Service located at [www.myfreakycreatures.com/TOS](http://www.myfreakycreatures.com/tos/). By using the Sites, you signify your assent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, you are not authorized to use the Sites or Services. We reserve the right to make changes in this Privacy Policy, provided that we give notice to you of any such changes via e-mail and/or by posting the amended Privacy Policy on the Sites. Please check back from time to time to ensure you are aware of any such notices of changes in our privacy practices. Your continued use of the Sites will signify your acceptance of these changes.
